<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../PSD_R2x3.xsl"?>
<PropertySetDef><IfcVersion version="2x3 TC1" schema="IfcProductExtension"/><Name>Pset_BuildingCommon</Name><Definition>Definition from IAI: Properties common to the definition of all instances of IfcBuilding. Please note that several building attributes are handled directly at the IfcBuilding instance, the building number (or short name) by IfcBuilding.Name, the building name (or long name) by IfcBuilding.LongName, and the description (or comments) by IfcBuilding.Description. Actual building quantities, like building perimeter, building area and building volume are provided by IfcElementQuantities, and the building classification according to national building code by IfcClassificationReference. </Definition><Applicability>IfcBuilding entity.</Applicability><ApplicableClasses><ClassName>IfcBuilding</ClassName></ApplicableClasses><ApplicableTypeValue></ApplicableTypeValue><PropertyDefs><PropertyDef><Name>BuildingID</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcIdentifier"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>A unique identifier assigned to a building. A temporary identifier is initially assigned at the time of making a planning application. This temporary identifier is changed to a permanent identifier when the building is registered into a statutory buildings and properties database.</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>IsPermanentID</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcBoolean"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>Indicates whether the identity assigned to a building is permanent (= TRUE) or temporary (=FALSE)</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>MainFireUse</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcLabel"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>Main fire use for the building which is assigned from the fire use classification table as given by the relevant national building code.</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>AncillaryFireUse</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcLabel"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>Ancillary fire use for the building which is assigned from the fire use classification table as given by the relevant national building code.</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>SprinklerProtection</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcBoolean"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>Indication whether this object is sprinkler protected (TRUE) or not (FALSE).</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>SprinklerProtectionAutomatic</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcBoolean"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>Indication whether this object has an automatic sprinkler protection (TRUE) or not (FALSE).
It should only be given, if the property "SprinklerProtection" is set to TRUE.</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>OccupancyType</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcLabel"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>Occupancy type for this object.
It is defined according to the presiding national building code.</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>GrossPlannedArea</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcAreaMeasure"/><UnitType type="AREAUNIT"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>Total planned area for the building  Used for programming the building.</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>NumberOfStoreys</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcInteger"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>Captures the number of storeys within a building for those cases where the IfcBuildingStorey entity is not used. Note that if IfcBuilingStorey is asserted and the number of storeys in a building can be determined from it, then this approach should be used in preference to setting a property for the number of storeys.</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>YearOfConstruction</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcLabel"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>Year of construction of this building, including expected year of completion.</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>IsLandmarked</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcLogical"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>This builing is listed as a historic building (TRUE), or not (FALSE), or unknown.</Definition></PropertyDef></PropertyDefs></PropertySetDef>
