<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../PSD_R2x3.xsl"?>
<PropertySetDef><IfcVersion version="2x3 TC1" schema="IfcProductExtension"/><Name>Pset_Draughting</Name><Definition>Definition from IAI: Property set to capture layer and colour as a quick win implementation within IFC2x platform to enable more efficient exchange of 3D building models.
NOTE: With implementation of the IFC2x2 capabilities defined in the presentation resources (IfcPresentationLayerAssignment, IfcCurveStyle) the use of this property set may become obsolete.</Definition><Applicability>selected subtypes of IfcProduct</Applicability><ApplicableClasses><ClassName>IfcElement</ClassName><ClassName>IfcSpatialStructureElement</ClassName></ApplicableClasses><ApplicableTypeValue></ApplicableTypeValue><PropertyDefs><PropertyDef><Name>LayerName</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcIdentifier"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>Identifier of the layer name within the sending application.</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>Colour</Name><PropertyType><TypeComplexProperty name="RGB_Colour"><PropertyDef><Name>Red</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcInteger"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>Red component of the RGB colour specification given by an integer of 0..255</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>Green</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcInteger"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>Green component of the RGB colour specification given by an integer of 0..256</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>Blue</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcInteger"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>Blue component of the RGB colour specification given by an integer of 0..257</Definition></PropertyDef></TypeComplexProperty></PropertyType><ValueDef><MinValue value=""/><MaxValue value=""/></ValueDef><Definition>Significant colour definition of the whole element for all shape representations, it is given for highlighting/differentiation purposes, full colour representation of individual geometric representation items, using the IFC2x2 presentation schemas, always takes precedence. In case of several colour information available (line, upper/lower surface, etc.) the sending application shall identify the most significant single colour to be included,</Definition></PropertyDef></PropertyDefs></PropertySetDef>
