<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../PSD_R2x3.xsl"?>
<PropertySetDef><IfcVersion version="2x3 TC1" schema="IfcProductExtension"/><Name>Pset_BuildingStoreyCommon</Name><Definition>Definition from IAI: Properties common to the definition of all instances of IfcBuildingStorey. Please note that several building attributes are handled directly at the IfcBuildingStorey instance, the building storey number (or short name) by IfcBuildingStorey.Name, the building storey name (or long name) by IfcBuildingStorey.LongName, and the description (or comments) by IfcBuildingStorey.Description. Actual building storey quantities, like building storey perimeter, building storey area and building storey volume are provided by IfcElementQuantities, and the building storey classification according to national building code by IfcClassificationReference. 
</Definition><Applicability>IfcBuildingStorey entity.</Applicability><ApplicableClasses><ClassName>IfcBuildingStorey</ClassName></ApplicableClasses><ApplicableTypeValue></ApplicableTypeValue><PropertyDefs><PropertyDef><Name>EntranceLevel</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcBoolean"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>Indication whether this building storey is an entrance level to the building (TRUE), or (FALSE) if otherwise.</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>AboveGround</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcLogical"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>Indication whether this building storey is fully above ground (TRUE), or below ground (FALSE), or partially above and below ground (UNKNOWN) - as in sloped terrain.</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>SprinklerProtection</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcBoolean"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>Indication whether this object is sprinkler protected (true) or not (false).</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>SprinklerProtectionAutomatic</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcBoolean"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>Indication whether this object has an automatic sprinkler protection (true) or not (false).
It should only be given, if the property "SprinklerProtection" is set to TRUE.</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>GrossAreaPlanned</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcAreaMeasure"/><UnitType type="AREAUNIT"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>Total planned area for the building storey. Used for programming the building storey.</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>NetAreaPlanned</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcAreaMeasure"/><UnitType type="AREAUNIT"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>Total planned net area for the building storey. Used for programming the building storey.</Definition></PropertyDef></PropertyDefs></PropertySetDef>
