<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../PSD_R2x3.xsl"?>
<PropertySetDef><IfcVersion version="2x3 TC1" schema="IfcHvacDomain"/><Name>Pset_GasTerminalTypeGasAppliance</Name><Definition>Definition from IAI: Piece of equipment for occupants use that is connected to a gas installation (definition is a modification from that found in BS6100).</Definition><Applicability>Entity specific property set</Applicability><ApplicableClasses><ClassName>IfcGasTerminalType</ClassName></ApplicableClasses><ApplicableTypeValue>IfcGasTerminalType.PredefinedType="GASAPPLIANCE"</ApplicableTypeValue><PropertyDefs><PropertyDef><Name>GasApplianceType</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertyEnumeratedValue><EnumList name="PEnum_GasApplianceType"><EnumItem>GASFIRE</EnumItem><EnumItem>GASCOOKER</EnumItem><EnumItem>OTHER</EnumItem><EnumItem>NOTKNOWN</EnumItem><EnumItem>UNSET</EnumItem></EnumList></TypePropertyEnumeratedValue></PropertyType><ValueDef><MinValue value=""/><MaxValue value=""/></ValueDef><Definition>Selection of the type of gas appliance from the enumerated list of types.</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>FlueType</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertyEnumeratedValue><EnumList name="PEnum_FlueType"><EnumItem>BALANCEDFLUE</EnumItem><EnumItem>FLUED</EnumItem><EnumItem>FLUELESS</EnumItem><EnumItem>OPENFLUED</EnumItem><EnumItem>ROOMSEALED</EnumItem><EnumItem>OTHER</EnumItem><EnumItem>NOTKNOWN</EnumItem><EnumItem>UNSET</EnumItem></EnumList></TypePropertyEnumeratedValue></PropertyType><ValueDef><MinValue value=""/><MaxValue value=""/></ValueDef><Definition>Defines the types of flue that may be specified for connection to gas appliances where:

BalancedFlue =	Room sealed appliance that has its inlet for combustion air and its outlet for products of combustion in adjacent external positions, disposed so that wind effects are substantially balanced between them.
Flued =	Gas burning appliance designed for connection to a flue system
Flueless =	Gas burning appliance designed for use without connection to a flue system
OpenFlued =	Gas burning appliance designed to be connected to an open flue system, combustion air being drawn from a room or internal space in which the gas burning appliance is installed
RoomSealed =	Gas burning appliance that has its combustion system, including air inlet and products outlet, isolated from a room or internal space in which the gas burning appliance is installed
</Definition></PropertyDef></PropertyDefs></PropertySetDef>
