<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../PSD_R2x3.xsl"?>
<PropertySetDef><IfcVersion version="2x3 TC1" schema="IfcHvacDomain"/><Name>Pset_ValveTypeCommon</Name><Definition>Definition from IAI: Valve type common attributes.
</Definition><Applicability>Entity common property set</Applicability><ApplicableClasses><ClassName>IfcValveType</ClassName></ApplicableClasses><ApplicableTypeValue></ApplicableTypeValue><PropertyDefs><PropertyDef><Name>ValvePattern</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertyEnumeratedValue><EnumList name="PEnum_ValvePattern"><EnumItem>SINGLEPORT</EnumItem><EnumItem>ANGLED_2_PORT</EnumItem><EnumItem>STRAIGHT_2_PORT</EnumItem><EnumItem>STRAIGHT_3_PORT</EnumItem><EnumItem>CROSSOVER_4_PORT</EnumItem><EnumItem>OTHER</EnumItem><EnumItem>NOTKNOWN</EnumItem><EnumItem>UNSET</EnumItem></EnumList></TypePropertyEnumeratedValue></PropertyType><ValueDef><MinValue value=""/><MaxValue value=""/></ValueDef><Definition>The configuration of the ports of a valve according to either the linear route taken by a fluid flowing through the valve or by the number of ports where:

SINGLEPORT = Valve that has a single entry port from the system that it serves, the exit port being to the surrounding environment.
ANGLED_2_PORT = Valve in which the direction of flow is changed through 90 degrees
STRAIGHT_2_PORT = Valve in which the flow is straight through
STRAIGHT_3_PORT = Valve with three separate ports
CROSSOVER_4_PORT = Valve with 4 separate ports
</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>ValveOperation</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertyEnumeratedValue><EnumList name="PEnum_ValveOperation"><EnumItem>DROPWEIGHT</EnumItem><EnumItem>FLOAT</EnumItem><EnumItem>HYDRAULIC</EnumItem><EnumItem>LEVER</EnumItem><EnumItem>LOCKSHIELD</EnumItem><EnumItem>MOTORIZED</EnumItem><EnumItem>PNEUMATIC</EnumItem><EnumItem>SOLENOID</EnumItem><EnumItem>SPRING</EnumItem><EnumItem>THERMOSTATIC</EnumItem><EnumItem>WHEEL</EnumItem><EnumItem>OTHER</EnumItem><EnumItem>NOTKNOWN</EnumItem><EnumItem>UNSET</EnumItem></EnumList></TypePropertyEnumeratedValue></PropertyType><ValueDef><MinValue value=""/><MaxValue value=""/></ValueDef><Definition>The method of valve operation where:

DROPWEIGHT = A valve that is closed by the action of a weighted lever being released, the weight normally being prevented from dropping by being held by a wire, the closure normally being made by the action of heat on a fusible link in the wire
FLOAT = A valve that is opened and closed by the action of a float that rises and falls with water level. The float may be a ball attached to a lever or other mechanism
HYDRAULIC = A valve that is opened and closed by hydraulic actuation
LEVER = A valve that is opened and closed by the action of a lever rotating the gate within the valve.
LOCKSHIELD = A valve that requires the use of a special lockshield key for opening and closing, the operating mechanism being protected by a shroud during normal operation.
MOTORIZED = A valve that is opened and closed by the action of an electric motor on an actuator
PNEUMATIC = A valve that is opened and closed by pneumatic actuation
SOLENOID = A valve that is normally held open by a magnetic field in a coil acting on the gate but that is closed immediately if the electrical current generating the magnetic field is removed. 
SPRING = A valve that is normally held in position by the pressure of a spring on a plate but that may be caused to open if the pressure of the fluid is sufficient to overcome the spring pressure. 
THERMOSTATIC = A valve in which the ports are opened or closed to maintain a required predetermined temperature.
WHEEL = A valve that is opened and closed by the action of a wheel moving the gate within the valve.</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>ValveMechanism</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertyEnumeratedValue><EnumList name="PEnum_ValveMechanism"><EnumItem>BALL</EnumItem><EnumItem>BUTTERFLY</EnumItem><EnumItem>CONFIGUREDGATE</EnumItem><EnumItem>GLAND</EnumItem><EnumItem>GLOBE</EnumItem><EnumItem>LUBRICATEDPLUG</EnumItem><EnumItem>NEEDLE</EnumItem><EnumItem>PARALLELSLIDE</EnumItem><EnumItem>PLUG</EnumItem><EnumItem>WEDGEGATE</EnumItem><EnumItem>OTHER</EnumItem><EnumItem>NOTKNOWN</EnumItem><EnumItem>UNSET</EnumItem></EnumList></TypePropertyEnumeratedValue></PropertyType><ValueDef><MinValue value=""/><MaxValue value=""/></ValueDef><Definition>The mechanism by which the valve function is achieved where:

BALL Valve that has a ported ball that can be turned relative to the body seat ports
BUTTERFLY Valve in which a streamlined disc pivots about a diametric axis
CONFIGUREDGATE Screwdown valve in which the closing gate is shaped in a configured manner to have a more precise control of pressure and flow change across the valve.
GLAND Valve with a tapered seating, in which a rotatable plug is retained by means of a gland and gland packing
GLOBE Screwdown valve that has a spherical body
LUBRICATEDPLUG Plug valve in which a lubricant is injected under pressure between the plug face and the body
NEEDLE Valve for regulating the flow in or from a pipe, in which a slender cone moves along the axis of flow to close against a fixed conical seat
PARALLELSLIDE Screwdown valve that has a machined plate that slides in formed grooves to form a seal
PLUG Valve that has a ported plug that can be turned relative to the body seat ports
WEDGEGATE Screwdown valve that has a wedge shaped plate fitting into tapered guides to form a seal</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>Size</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcPositiveLengthMeasure"/><UnitType type="LENGTHUNIT"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>The size of the connection to the valve (or to each connection for faucets, mixing valves, etc.)</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>BodyMaterial</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertyReferenceValue reftype="IfcMaterial"/></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>Material from which the body of the valve is constructed</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>OperatingMechanismMaterial</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertyReferenceValue reftype="IfcMaterial"/></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>Material from which the operating mechanism (gate, globe, plug, needle, clack etc.) of the valve is constructed</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>TestPressure</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcPressureMeasure"/><UnitType type="PRESSUREUNIT"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>The maximum pressure to which the valve has been subjected under test</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>WorkingPressure</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcPressureMeasure"/><UnitType type="PRESSUREUNIT"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>The normally expected maximum working pressure of the valve</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>FlowCoefficient</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcReal"/><UnitType type="USERDEFINED"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>Flow coefficient (the quantity of fluid that passes through a fully open valve at unit pressure drop), typically expressed as the Kv or Cv value for the valve.</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>CloseOffRating</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcPressureMeasure"/><UnitType type="PRESSUREUNIT"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>Close off rating.</Definition></PropertyDef></PropertyDefs></PropertySetDef>
