<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../PSD_R2x3.xsl"?>
<PropertySetDef><IfcVersion version="2x3 TC1" schema="IfcPlumbingFireProtectionDomain"/><Name>Pset_SanitaryTerminalTypeCistern</Name><Definition>Definition from IAI: A water storage unit attached to a sanitary terminal that is fitted with a device, operated automatically or by the user, that discharges water to cleanse a water closet (toilet) pan, urinal or slop hopper. (BS6100 330 5008)</Definition><Applicability>IfcSanitaryTerminalType entity.</Applicability><ApplicableClasses><ClassName>IfcSanitaryTerminalType</ClassName></ApplicableClasses><ApplicableTypeValue>IfcSanitaryTerminalType.PredefinedType="CISTERN"</ApplicableTypeValue><PropertyDefs><PropertyDef><Name>CisternHeight</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertyEnumeratedValue><EnumList name="PEnum_CisternHeight"><EnumItem>HighLevel</EnumItem><EnumItem>LowLevel</EnumItem><EnumItem>None</EnumItem><EnumItem>Other</EnumItem><EnumItem>NotKnown</EnumItem><EnumItem>Unset</EnumItem></EnumList></TypePropertyEnumeratedValue></PropertyType><ValueDef><MinValue value=""/><MaxValue value=""/></ValueDef><Definition>Enumeration that identifies the height of the cistern or, if set to 'None' if the urinal has no cistern and is flushed using mains or high pressure water through a flushing valve.</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>CisternCapacity</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcVolumeMeasure"/><UnitType type="VOLUMEUNIT"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>Volumetric capacity of the cistern</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>IsSingleFlush</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcBoolean"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>Indicates whether the cistern is single flush = TRUE (i.e. the same amount of water is used for each and every flush) or dual flush = FALSE (i.e. the amount of water used for a flush may be selected by the user to be high or low depending on the waste material to be removed)</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>FlushType</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertyEnumeratedValue><EnumList name="PEnum_FlushType"><EnumItem>Lever</EnumItem><EnumItem>Pull</EnumItem><EnumItem>Push</EnumItem><EnumItem>Sensor</EnumItem><EnumItem>Other</EnumItem><EnumItem>NotKnown</EnumItem><EnumItem>Unset
</EnumItem></EnumList></TypePropertyEnumeratedValue></PropertyType><ValueDef><MinValue value=""/><MaxValue value=""/></ValueDef><Definition>The property enumeration Pset_FlushTypeEnum defines the types of flushing mechanism that may be specified for cisterns and sanitary terminals where:-

Lever =	Flushing is achieved by twisting a lever that causes a predetermined flow of water to be passed from a cistern to the sanitary terminal.
Pull =	Flushing is achieved by pulling a handle or knob vertically upwards that causes a predetermined flow of water to be passed from a cistern to the sanitary terminal.
Push =	Flushing is achieved by pushing a button or plate that causes a predetermined flow of water to be passed from a cistern to the sanitary terminal.
Sensor = Flush is activated through an automatic sensing mechanism.
</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>FlushRate</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertyBoundedValue><ValueRangeDef><LowerBoundValue value="?"/><UpperBoundValue value="?"/></ValueRangeDef><DataType type="IfcVolumeMeasure"/><UnitType type="VOLUMEUNIT"/></TypePropertyBoundedValue></PropertyType><ValueDef><MinValue value="?"/><MaxValue value="?"/></ValueDef><Definition>The minimum and maximum volume of water used at each flush. Where a single flush is used, the value of upper bound and lower bound should be equal. For a dual flush toilet, the lower bound should be used for the lesser flush rate and the upper bound for the greater flush rate. Where flush is achieved using mains pressure water through a flush valve, the value of upper and lower bound should be equal and should be the same as the flush rate property of the flush valve (see relevant valve property set). Alternatively, in this case, do not assert the flush rate property; refer to the flush rate of the flush valve.</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>IsAutomaticFlush</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcBoolean"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>Boolean value that determines if the cistern is flushed automatically either after each use or periodically (TRUE) or whether manual flushing is required (FALSE)</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>CisternMaterial</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertyReferenceValue reftype="IfcMaterial"/></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>Material from which the object is constructed</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>CisternColor</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcText"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>Color of the object</Definition></PropertyDef></PropertyDefs></PropertySetDef>
