<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../PSD_R2x3.xsl"?>
<PropertySetDef><IfcVersion version="2x3 TC1" schema="IfcSharedFacilitiesElements"/><Name>Pset_FurnitureTypeCommon</Name><Definition>Definition from IAI: Common properties for all types of furniture such as chair, desk, table, and file cabinet. HISTORY: First issued in IFC Release R1.5. Renamed from Pset_FurnitureCommon</Definition><Applicability>IfcFurnitureType entity</Applicability><ApplicableClasses><ClassName>IfcFurnitureType</ClassName></ApplicableClasses><ApplicableTypeValue></ApplicableTypeValue><PropertyDefs><PropertyDef><Name>Description</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcText"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>Specific description of this type of furniture.</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>Style</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcLabel"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>Description of the furniture style</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>NominalHeight</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcPositiveLengthMeasure "/><UnitType type="LENGTHUNIT"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>The nominal height of the furniture of this type. The size information is provided in addition to the shape representation and the geometric parameters used within. In cases of inconsistency between the geometric parameters and the size properties, provided in the attached property set, the geometric parameters take precedence.</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>NominalLength</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcPositiveLengthMeasure "/><UnitType type="LENGTHUNIT"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>The nominal length of the furniture of this type. The size information is provided in addition to the shape representation and the geometric parameters used within. In cases of inconsistency between the geometric parameters and the size properties, provided in the attached property set, the geometric parameters take precedence.</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>NominalDepth</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcPositiveLengthMeasure "/><UnitType type="LENGTHUNIT"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>The nominal depth of the furniture of this type. The size information is provided in addition to the shape representation and the geometric parameters used within. In cases of inconsistency between the geometric parameters and the size properties, provided in the attached property set, the geometric parameters take precedence.</Definition></PropertyDef><PropertyDef><Name>MainColor</Name><PropertyType><TypePropertySingleValue><DataType type="IfcLabel"/></TypePropertySingleValue></PropertyType><ValueDef/><Definition>The main color of the furniture of this type</Definition></PropertyDef></PropertyDefs></PropertySetDef>
